Guide to the Adolph Wittemann Photographs of Buildings and Grounds of Yale and New Haven Used in the Publication "New Haven and Yale University"
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Adolph Wittemann photographs of buildings and grounds of Yale and New Haven used in the publication "New Haven and Yale University"
1896-1901
RU 633
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
(1 box)
The collection consists of prints of various Yale and New Haven, Connecticut buildings and grounds taken by Adolph Wittemann for the souvenir publication "New Haven and Yale University." Included are views of Woolsey Hall, College Row, the New Haven Green, East Rock, Temple Street, and Sheffield Scientific School.
Wittemann, A. (Adolph), 1845-1938
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 46-A (YRG 46-A), Records and materials broadly documenting Yale buildings, facilities, and grounds.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
Arranged by subject.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of prints of various Yale and New Haven, Connecticut buildings and grounds taken by Adolph Wittemann for the souvenir publication New Haven and Yale University. Included are views of Woolsey Hall, College Row, the New Haven Green, East Rock, Temple Street, and Sheffield Scientific School.
College buildings; New Haven (Conn.) -- Pictorial works; Photographs; Wittemann, A. (Adolph), 1845-1938; Yale University -- Pictorial works; Yale University -- Buildings
- Photographs, Series I
  - Woolsey Hall, circa 1896 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Church Street, south from Chapel, circa 1896 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - College Row on a sunday afternoon, circa 1896 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Hillhouse Avenue, circa 1896 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Sheffield Scientific School, circa 1896 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - College Street, circa 1896 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Various New Haven buildings, circa 1896 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - The Green with City Hall and Superior Court House, circa 1896 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - White, Berkely and Fairweather Halls, circa 1896 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - East Rock and Soldiers' Monument, circa 1896 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - West Rock, circa 1896 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Commons -interior, circa 1896 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Soldiers' Monument from Farnam Drive, circa 1896 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Soldiers' Monument -East Rock Park, circa 1896 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Lake Whitney from Farnam Drive, circa 1896 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Savin Rock -Fountain and Pavilion, circa 1896 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Noble elm -the Green, circa 1896 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Temple Street -North and Center Churches, circa 1896 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Elm Street from Church Street, circa 1896 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Osborn Hall and College Street, circa 1896 (Box 1, Folder 7)